There could be malware lurking right underneath your fingertips.
Just by breaking down the word malware you can assume its meaning.
The Latin root word mal,
meaning bad or evil,
like malicious malfunction and even dismal,
plusware,
referring to computer software,
equates to bad software.
Malware is any program or file harmful to a user.
Types of malware include viruses which work on
their own and spread to other programs,
worms which self-replicate and spread autonomously.
Trojan horses,
which are disguised as legitimate programs to gain access to a system,
spyware,
which discreetly collects user information and activity,
ransomware,
which encrypts a user's data and demands payment,
and others like rootkits,
adware,
backdoor viruses,
and key loggers.
Malware authors usually want to steal financial,
personal,
or corporate information
to target advertisements or to control the device completely within a botnet.
Some malware can be easily detected
either by observing unusual activity or with antivirus software,
and some can be removed.
Having a malware response plan in place is key to lowering the chances of an attack
and key to recovering from one.
Have you had any malware run-ins?
Share your experience in the comments and please hit that like button.